

KEHINDE MURAINA

Kehinde.murainaa@gmail.com | +(234) 7080828544 | Lagos Nigeria

Summary

Muraina Kehinde is a top management expert with over 7+ years of extensive pan-African and global experiences in the use of technology, design, and innovation for development. As a TEDx Speaker, Tony Elumelu mentor, and YALI West African fellow, Kehinde's expertise is sought after by top organizations globally. He has been recognized for his contributions to development, innovation, and shared mutual prosperity in Africa.

Education

Quantic School of Business And Technology Executive Masters of Business Administration in Strategic Leadership 09/2024

University of Ibadan | Ibadan **Bachelor of Medical Laboratory Science (B.MLS)** 01/2017

Strengths

- Program management
- Stakeholder engagement
- Partnerships
- Grant management
- Innovation

- Strategic leadership
- Operational efficiency
- Service delivery
- Process optimization

Professional Experience

| Nigeria

Senior Consultant

11/2022 - Current

- Clinton Health Access Initiative (CHAI) Led a 20-man team to implement health technology solutions, optimize processes, and improve service delivery, ensuring alignment with organizational goals.
 - Managed four projects worth \$4.13M, focusing on boosting operational efficiency through technology.
 - Developed forecasting and procurement strategies to streamline operations across multiple regions, ensuring cost-effective resource management.
 - Built forecasting models that supported long-term project success, benefiting over 9,000+ patients

| Lagos, Nigeria Consultant (Service Delivery & **Impact Evaluation**)

- Clinton Health Access Initiative (CHAI) Spearheaded a \$3M initiative focused on improving project impact through effective service delivery and data-driven evaluation, achieving significant results in a two-year period.
 - Developed a comprehensive investment case for sustainable financing,

Healthstacks | Lagos, Nigeria **Country Lead** 01/2021 - 01/2022

- engaging both public and private sector stakeholders to align project goals with broader funding strategies.
- Designed and implemented a data visualization tool to enhance decision-making and operational efficiency, driving improvements in service delivery.

• Provided strategic leadership for a team of 20, driving the execution of technology-driven solutions across multiple sectors, improving data management, and operational processes.

- Secured \$15K in seed funding to develop a digital records system, resulting in improved operational efficiency and scalability across various facilities.
- Collaborated with teams and external stakeholders to align project execution with organizational goals, delivering measurable results and driving the adoption of innovative solutions.

Co-Creation Hub Nigeria | Nigeria Senior Associate 06/2020 - 08/2021

- Led the design and execution of a \$100K project aimed at improving operational processes through innovative technologies.
- Managed external stakeholder engagements, securing funding opportunities from Merck, MIT, and the Gates Foundation.
- Supported the successful execution of a \$50K data management project in Lagos and Ondo states.

Health Strategy and Delivery Foundation | Lagos, Nigeria **Program Analyst** 11/2019 - 05/2020

- Coordinated a 5-month Maternal and Newborn Quality Improvement (QI) project across 3 public secondary health facilities in Lagos, Nigeria
- Routinely engaged senior management and stakeholders to align project activities with key organizational objectives.
- Designed 3 critical solutions for improving the quality of care and service delivery received by women, contributing to better project performance in the public sector.

Young African Leaders Initiative (YALI) Network | Oyo State, Nigeria **State Lead** 01/2017 - 12/2019

- Young African Leaders Initiative (YALI) Led a network of 2,000+ members, managing 10 key projects focused Network | Oyo State, Nigeria on waste management, civic engagement, and public policy.
 - Served as the focal point between Oyo state and the US government, ensuring successful project implementation.
 - Coordinated leadership programs and stakeholder partnerships for community and state-level impact.

Externalstakeholderengagement

- Collaborated with organizations including Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation, Meta (Facebook), WHO, and British Council.
- Fostered partnerships with government ministries, international donors, and private sector players across Africa.
- Secured and managed multi-million-dollar collaborations with international funders and local partners.

Leadership Experience

- Mentor, Tony Elumelu Foundation, 2021, 2022
- Ambassador (West/Central Africa), UN Major Group of Children and Youths, 2017

Awards

- Most Influential Young Person in Africa Opportunities Hub | 2022
- TEDx Speaker, TEDxUCHIbadan | 2021
- Human Centered Design Fellowship, Co-Creation Design Lab (Sponsored by the Gates Foundation) | 2019
- Fellow, Young African Leaders Initiative | 2018
- 1st Runner Up, 3D Africa HackforGood Hardware Hackathon | 2017

Certifications

- Human-Centered Design | Co-Creation Hub & Gates Foundation (2019)
- Managerial Economics | LinkedIn Learning (2021)
- Project Management (International Projects) | LinkedIn Learning (2021)

References

Available upon request.